<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Hugo-HT</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Hugo-HT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:20:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ybfan115.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mapping Online Communities</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mapping-online-communities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:20:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mapping-online-communities/</guid><description>This project directed by Nate aims to map two online communities which are fandom wiki and reddit. By computational methods, we try to find out how associated the fandom wikis and subreddits are, to further find out the features of the intergroup relationship.
I am playing a role in building the dataset. Here are my notes about how we organize the data, and what skills and ideas I have got from the project.</description></item><item><title>Media Multitasking and Emotional Change</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/media-multitasking-and-emotional-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:20:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/media-multitasking-and-emotional-change/</guid><description>This project begins with my coursework on Communication Cognition, which is a graduate-level seminar given by Prof. Yegiyan at UC Davis. I accomplished the research proposal on this seminar and am collecting data now.
Key Concepts Self-control: the mental processes which allow people to make their thoughts, emotions, and behaviors consistent with their long-term targets (Inzlicht, Schmeichel, &amp;amp; Macrae, 2014)
Two models for self-control
Strength model of self-control (Baumeister et al.</description></item><item><title>Listening to the ancient opera: Sound studies and media history</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/listening-to-the-ancient-opera-sound-studies-and-media-history/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:19:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/listening-to-the-ancient-opera-sound-studies-and-media-history/</guid><description>Abstract: This project was conducted during the directed reading workshop hosted by Prof. Wang at Renmin University on STS studies. It used archival study to link the emerging theoretical turn in STS - sound studies and media history, and found that (1) the sound of ancient opera could contribute to shaping the embodied experience of audience; (2) various kinds of social relationships were mediated by the sound due to its features as a medium.</description></item><item><title>Mediated Local Governance in China</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mediated-local-governance-in-china/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 14:49:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mediated-local-governance-in-china/</guid><description>Undergraduate research project, 09/20 - 05/21 Presentation on undergraduate academic works competition Advisor: Associate Professor Yan Yan (Ph.D. in communication at University of Alabama) Background Internet and technology use have changed the government behavior and the public life. In China, a large number of government related official accounts on Weibo (which is a Chinese online platform like Twitter) has been run to better conduct governance.
This project was focused on a typical set of official accounts run by departments of the local government in a particular district.</description></item><item><title>RA Notes</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/08/30/ra-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 15:31:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/08/30/ra-notes/</guid><description>Notes: This post is written to keep the ideas alive and document what I learn from the research work with Nate . Since Aug. 2021, I began to contribute to the project of Nate which is intended to find the connections between two online communities - Fandom wiki (which was previously known as Wikia) and Reddit . I make a role in the dataset construction.
Wikidata and SPARQL language: Wikidata is an open source knowledge graph that has structured data about relationships between different entities.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/posts/2021/08/22/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/posts/2021/08/22/introduction/</guid><description>I am Yibin, an undergraduate majoring in communication at Renmin University of China. This is my first blog.
I am interested in two research fields: organizational communication, especially the research of online communities, such as Wikipedia, FoSS, and so on; and STS studies, especially sound studies, which is an emerging topic these years.
I am going to apply for graduate schools later this year, so I am devoted in the preparation for my application.</description></item><item><title>Dataset Notes</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/26/dataset-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:35:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/26/dataset-notes/</guid><description>The Upworthy Research Archive The Upworthy Research Archive is an open dataset of thousands of A/B tests of headlines conducted by Upworthy from January 2013 to April 2015. In August 2021, this archive has been public and intended to promote the knowledge in polical science, communication, and other fields.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Community Genealogy</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/24/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/24/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</guid><description>This is the reading notes for the paper:
Tan, C. (2018, June). Tracing community genealogy: how new communities emerge from the old. In Twelfth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media.
The author&amp;rsquo;s work are wonderful with a focus on the relationship of online communities.</description></item><item><title>Happy Learning: Crash Course</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/happy-learning-crash-course/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:57:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/happy-learning-crash-course/</guid><description>Crash Course AI Natural Language Processing Two major topics: natural language understanding,</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Disinformation across Platforms</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/paper-notes-disinformation-across-platforms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:18:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/paper-notes-disinformation-across-platforms/</guid><description>This is reading notes for this articles:
Starbird, K., &amp;amp; Wilson, T. (2020). Cross-platform disinformation campaigns: Lessons learned and next steps. Harvard Kennedy School (HKS) Misinformation Review. https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-002[https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-002]
Research Question: How do disinformation campaigns work ==across online platforms== to achieve their strategic goals? How do governments and other political entities support disinformation campaigns? Summary Methods: mix-method approach to examine digital trace data Mapping the structure of the Twitter conversation around White Helmets, identifying a pro-White Helmets cluster and an anti-White Helmets cluster.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/22/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/22/introduction/</guid><description>I am Yibin, an undergraduate majoring in communication at Renmin University of China. This is my first blog.
I am interested in two research fields: organizational communication, especially the research of online communities, such as Wikipedia, FoSS, and so on; and STS studies, especially sound studies, which is an emerging topic these years.
I am going to apply for graduate schools later this year, so I am devoted in the preparation for my application.</description></item><item><title>Markdown 试水</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/cn/2021/01/07/first-post-cn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 13:42:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/cn/2021/01/07/first-post-cn/</guid><description>如果好奇以下的内容是如何实现的，请看本页源代码 。
第一级标题 第二级标题 第三级标题 第四级标题 第五级标题 第六级标题 列表 Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water 表格 Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water1 Water Water Water Water 引语 知之为知之，不知为不知，是知也2。 — 孔子
数学公式 最简单的如，$1 + 1 = 3$</description></item><item><title>背影</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/cn/1925/10/01/beiying/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 1925 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/cn/1925/10/01/beiying/</guid><description>我与父亲不相见已二年余了，我最不能忘记的是他的背影。那年冬天，祖母死了，父亲的差使也交卸了，正是祸不单行的日子，我从北京到徐州，打算跟着父亲奔丧回家。到徐州见着父亲，看见满院狼藉的东西，又想起祖母，不禁簌簌地流下眼泪。父亲说，“事已如此，不必难过，好在天无绝人之路！”
　回家变卖典质，父亲还了亏空；又借钱办了丧事。这些日子，家中光景很是惨淡，一半为了丧事，一半为了父亲赋闲。丧事完毕，父亲要到南京谋事，我也要回北京念书，我们便同行。
　到南京时，有朋友约去游逛，勾留了一日；第二日上午便须渡江到浦口，下午上车北去。父亲因为事忙，本已说定不送我，叫旅馆里一个熟识的茶房陪我同去。他再三嘱咐茶房，甚是仔细。但他终于不放心，怕茶房不妥帖；颇踌躇了一会。其实我那年已二十岁，北京已来往过两三次，是没有甚么要紧的了。他踌躇了一会，终于决定还是自己送我去。我两三回劝他不必去；他只说，“不要紧，他们去不好！”
　我们过了江，进了车站。我买票，他忙着照看行李。行李太多了，得向脚夫行些小费，才可过去。他便又忙着和他们讲价钱。我那时真是聪明过分，总觉他说话不大漂亮，非自己插嘴不可。但他终于讲定了价钱；就送我上车。他给我拣定了靠车门的一张椅子；我将他给我做的紫毛大衣铺好坐位。他嘱我路上小心，夜里警醒些，不要受凉。又嘱托茶房好好照应我。我心里暗笑他的迂；他们只认得钱，托他们直是白托！而且我这样大年纪的人，难道还不能料理自己么？唉，我现在想想，那时真是太聪明了！
　我说道，“爸爸，你走吧。”他望车外看了看，说，“我买几个橘子去。你就在此地，不要走动。”我看那边月台的栅栏外有几个卖东西的等着顾客。走到那边月台，须穿过铁道，须跳下去又爬上去。父亲是一个胖子，走过去自然要费事些。我本来要去的，他不肯，只好让他去。我看见他戴着黑布小帽，穿着黑布大马褂，深青布棉袍，蹒跚地走到铁道边，慢慢探身下去，尚不大难。可是他穿过铁道，要爬上那边月台，就不容易了。他用两手攀着上面，两脚再向上缩；他肥胖的身子向左微倾，显出努力的样子。这时我看见他的背影，我的泪很快地流下来了。我赶紧拭干了泪，怕他看见，也怕别人看见。我再向外看时，他已抱了朱红的橘子望回走了。过铁道时，他先将橘子散放在地上，自己慢慢爬下，再抱起橘子走。到这边时，我赶紧去搀他。他和我走到车上，将橘子一股脑儿放在我的皮大衣上。于是扑扑衣上的泥土，心里很轻松似的，过一会说，“我走了；到那边来信！”我望着他走出去。他走了几步，回过头看见我，说，“进去吧，里边没人。”等他的背影混入来来往往的人里，再找不着了，我便进来坐下，我的眼泪又来了。
　近几年来，父亲和我都是东奔西走，家中光景是一日不如一日。他少年出外谋生，独力支持，做了许多大事。那知老境却如此颓唐！他触目伤怀，自然情不能自已。情郁于中，自然要发之于外；家庭琐屑便往往触他之怒。他待我渐渐不同往日。但最近两年的不见，他终于忘却我的不好，只是惦记着我，惦记着我的儿子。我北来后，他写了一信给我，信中说道，“我身体平安，惟膀子疼痛利害，举箸提笔，诸多不便，大约大去之期不远矣。”我读到此处，在晶莹的泪光中，又看见那肥胖的，青布棉袍，黑布马褂的背影。唉！我不知何时再能与他相见！</description></item></channel></rss>