<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Posts on Hugo-HT</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in English Posts on Hugo-HT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 15:31:09 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ybfan115.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RA Notes</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/08/30/ra-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 15:31:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/08/30/ra-notes/</guid><description>Notes: This post is written to keep the ideas alive and document what I learn from the research work with Nate . Since Aug. 2021, I began to contribute to the project of Nate which is intended to find the connections between two online communities - Fandom wiki (which was previously known as Wikia) and Reddit . I make a role in the dataset construction.
Wikidata and SPARQL language: Wikidata is an open source knowledge graph that has structured data about relationships between different entities.</description></item><item><title>Dataset Notes</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/26/dataset-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:35:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/26/dataset-notes/</guid><description>The Upworthy Research Archive The Upworthy Research Archive is an open dataset of thousands of A/B tests of headlines conducted by Upworthy from January 2013 to April 2015. In August 2021, this archive has been public and intended to promote the knowledge in polical science, communication, and other fields.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Community Genealogy</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/24/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/24/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</guid><description>This is the reading notes for the paper:
Tan, C. (2018, June). Tracing community genealogy: how new communities emerge from the old. In Twelfth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media.
The author&amp;rsquo;s work are wonderful with a focus on the relationship of online communities.</description></item><item><title>Happy Learning: Crash Course</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/happy-learning-crash-course/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:57:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/happy-learning-crash-course/</guid><description>Crash Course AI Natural Language Processing Two major topics: natural language understanding,</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Disinformation across Platforms</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/paper-notes-disinformation-across-platforms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:18:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/paper-notes-disinformation-across-platforms/</guid><description>This is reading notes for this articles:
Starbird, K., &amp;amp; Wilson, T. (2020). Cross-platform disinformation campaigns: Lessons learned and next steps. Harvard Kennedy School (HKS) Misinformation Review. https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-002[https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-002]
Research Question: How do disinformation campaigns work ==across online platforms== to achieve their strategic goals? How do governments and other political entities support disinformation campaigns? Summary Methods: mix-method approach to examine digital trace data Mapping the structure of the Twitter conversation around White Helmets, identifying a pro-White Helmets cluster and an anti-White Helmets cluster.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/22/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ybfan115.github.io/en/2021/07/22/introduction/</guid><description>I am Yibin, an undergraduate majoring in communication at Renmin University of China. This is my first blog.
I am interested in two research fields: organizational communication, especially the research of online communities, such as Wikipedia, FoSS, and so on; and STS studies, especially sound studies, which is an emerging topic these years.
I am going to apply for graduate schools later this year, so I am devoted in the preparation for my application.</description></item></channel></rss>