<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Posts on Hugo-HT</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in English Posts on Hugo-HT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 16:37:57 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://YbFan115.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paper Notes: Hanging out or figuring out in online community</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/10/11/paper-notes-hanging-out-or-figuring-out-in-online-community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/10/11/paper-notes-hanging-out-or-figuring-out-in-online-community/</guid><description>Shorey, Hill, &amp;amp; Woolley, 2021
Abstract &amp;ldquo;participatory debugging&amp;rdquo; - collaborative technical troubleshooting quali - analysis of user activity over time and identify three factors as social antecedents of participatory debugging: sustained community, identifiable problems, topic porousness which means conversations can span multiple topics. give a framework which highlights a productive tension between the desire to promote learning and interest-driven sub-communities Background Participantory media environments are characterized by low barriers for engagement, an emphasis on sharing, informal mentorship between experienced members and novices, and feelings of connection among members of the group.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: How individual behavior drives community size inequality</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/10/02/paper-notes-how-individual-behavior-drives-community-size-inequality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/10/02/paper-notes-how-individual-behavior-drives-community-size-inequality/</guid><description>Foote, Teblunthuis, Hill, &amp;amp; Shaw, 2018
Abstract
Why are online community sizes so extremely unequal? Cumulative advantage - however, it cannot provide explanation for specific social dynamics, agency of users in communities, and lack a clear link to individual-level behavior. Agent-based Simulation Test whether individual-level processes of social exposure and decisions based on individual expected benefits reproduce the size data from Reddit Both processes together (but neither alone) contribute to distributions of community sizes.</description></item><item><title>RA Notes</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/30/ra-notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 15:31:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/30/ra-notes/</guid><description>Notes: This post is written to keep the ideas alive and document what I learn from the research work with Nate . Since Aug. 2021, I began to contribute to the project of Nate which is intended to find the connections between two online communities - Fandom wiki (which was previously known as Wikia) and Reddit . I make a role in the dataset construction.
Wikidata and SPARQL language: Wikidata is an open source knowledge graph that has structured data about relationships between different entities.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Why Small Communities</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/28/paper-notes-why-small-communities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/28/paper-notes-why-small-communities/</guid><description> The small scale makes people in the communities have control on their experiences, curating content and users that is predictable and navigable.
Future direction: how communities of different sizes operate and interact in community ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Network structure and behavior diffusion</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/23/paper-notes-network-structure-and-behavior-diffusion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/23/paper-notes-network-structure-and-behavior-diffusion/</guid><description>Hsiao, 2021
Abstract
tested three well-known factors of single behavior diffusion - network transitivity, adoption threshold, and connectedness of early adopters - apply to scenarios of competitive diffusion simulation study Intro
Research question: when multiple orgs compete for behavioral adoption, which org would prevail? One way to explain how behaviors got adopted is through understanding social networks. ==how interactions among multi online communities bring behavior change?</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Community Governance</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/12/paper-notes-community-governance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/12/paper-notes-community-governance/</guid><description>Schneider, de Filippi, Frey, Tan, &amp;amp; Zhang, 2021
Abstract Modular Politics would enable platform operators and their users to build bottom-up governance processes from computational components that are modular and composable, highly versatile in their expressiveness, portable from one context to another, and interoperable across platforms
==another reason for study the relationship among platforms or communities== Intro (1) Modularity: Platform operators and community members should have the ability to construct systems by creating, importing, and arranging composable parts together as a coherent whole.</description></item><item><title>List of Papers on analysis of community level</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/28/list-of-papers-on-analysis-of-community-level/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/28/list-of-papers-on-analysis-of-community-level/</guid><description>[[Assembly in populations of social networks]]
[[All who wander on the prevalence and characteristics in the multi-community engagement]]
[[Modular Politics]]
[[Using machine learning to learn machine]]
methodology: combine machine learning and online experiment [[Network diffusion of competing behaviors]]
[[From hanging out to figuring it out - socializing online as a pathway to computational thinking]]
[[Why people participate in small online communities]]</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Community Genealogy</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/27/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/27/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</guid><description>This is the reading notes for the paper:
Tan, C. (2018, June). Tracing community genealogy: how new communities emerge from the old. In Twelfth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media.
The author&amp;rsquo;s work are wonderful with a focus on the relationship of online communities.
The project will study the emergence of online groups by examining their overlooked but important connections to existing groups. New online groups do not appear spontaneously, but are created by users who participated in existing online groups.</description></item><item><title>Dataset Notes</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/26/dataset-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 20:35:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/26/dataset-notes/</guid><description>The Upworthy Research Archive The Upworthy Research Archive is an open dataset of thousands of A/B tests of headlines conducted by Upworthy from January 2013 to April 2015. In August 2021, this archive has been public and intended to promote the knowledge in polical science, communication, and other fields. This dataset can be used to develop large-scale online experiments research.
The Pushshift Reddit Dataset Pushshift is a social media data collection, analysis, and archiving platform that since 2015 has collected Reddit data and made it available to researchers.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Assembly of networks</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/25/paper-notes-assembly-of-networks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/25/paper-notes-assembly-of-networks/</guid><description>Jacobs, 2018
Abstract
With single examples, we can not in general know how much of observed network structure is explained by historical accidents, random noise, or meaningful social processes, nor can we claim that network structure predicts outcomes, such as organization success or ecosystem health.
Notes: There are many questions which could not be explained by the current research on network structure in single examples, including whether the formation of the structure results from historical and political contigencies, or substantial social change processes; or how can network structure predict outcomes like organization success and ecosystem health.</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Community Genealogy</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/24/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 16:37:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/24/paper-notes-community-genealogy/</guid><description>Tan &amp;amp; Lee, 2015
Abstract Although analyzing user behavior within individual communities is an active and rich research domain, people usually interact with multiple communities both on- and off-line.</description></item><item><title>Happy Learning: Crash Course</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/happy-learning-crash-course/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:57:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/happy-learning-crash-course/</guid><description>Crash Course AI Natural Language Processing Two major topics: natural language understanding,</description></item><item><title>Paper Notes: Disinformation across Platforms</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/paper-notes-disinformation-across-platforms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:18:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/23/paper-notes-disinformation-across-platforms/</guid><description>This is reading notes for this articles:
Starbird, K., &amp;amp; Wilson, T. (2020). Cross-platform disinformation campaigns: Lessons learned and next steps. Harvard Kennedy School (HKS) Misinformation Review. https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-002[https://doi.org/10.37016/mr-2020-002]
Research Question: How do disinformation campaigns work ==across online platforms== to achieve their strategic goals? How do governments and other political entities support disinformation campaigns? Summary Methods: mix-method approach to examine digital trace data Mapping the structure of the Twitter conversation around White Helmets, identifying a pro-White Helmets cluster and an anti-White Helmets cluster.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/22/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/07/22/introduction/</guid><description>I am Yibin, an undergraduate majoring in communication at Renmin University of China. This is my first blog.
I am interested in two research fields: organizational communication, especially the research of online communities, such as Wikipedia, FoSS, and so on; and STS studies, especially sound studies, which is an emerging topic these years.
I am going to apply for graduate schools later this year, so I am devoted in the preparation for my application.</description></item></channel></rss>