<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo-HT</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/projects/</link><description>Recent content on Hugo-HT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:20:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://YbFan115.github.io/en/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mapping Online Communities</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mapping-online-communities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:20:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mapping-online-communities/</guid><description>This project directed by Nate aims to map two online communities which are fandom wiki and reddit. By computational methods, we try to find out how associated the fandom wikis and subreddits are, to further find out the features of the intergroup relationship.
I am playing a role in building the dataset. Here are my notes about how we organize the data, and what skills and ideas I have got from the project.</description></item><item><title>Media Multitasking and Emotional Change</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/media-multitasking-and-emotional-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:20:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/media-multitasking-and-emotional-change/</guid><description>This project begins with my coursework on Communication Cognition, which is a graduate-level seminar given by Prof. Yegiyan at UC Davis. I accomplished the research proposal on this seminar and am collecting data now.
Key Concepts Self-control: the mental processes which allow people to make their thoughts, emotions, and behaviors consistent with their long-term targets (Inzlicht, Schmeichel, &amp;amp; Macrae, 2014)
Two models for self-control
Strength model of self-control (Baumeister et al.</description></item><item><title>Listening to the ancient opera: Sound studies and media history</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/listening-to-the-ancient-opera-sound-studies-and-media-history/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 15:19:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/listening-to-the-ancient-opera-sound-studies-and-media-history/</guid><description>Abstract: This project was conducted during the directed reading workshop hosted by Prof. Wang at Renmin University on STS studies. It used archival study to link the emerging theoretical turn in STS - sound studies and media history, and found that (1) the sound of ancient opera could contribute to shaping the embodied experience of audience; (2) various kinds of social relationships were mediated by the sound due to its features as a medium.</description></item><item><title>Mediated Local Governance in China</title><link>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mediated-local-governance-in-china/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 14:49:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://YbFan115.github.io/en/2021/09/10/mediated-local-governance-in-china/</guid><description>Funded Undergraduate research project, 09/20 - 05/21 Advisor: Associate Professor Yan Yan (Ph.D. in communication at University of Alabama) Background Internet technology use has changed the government behavior and the public life. In China, a large number of government-related official accounts on Weibo (which is a Chinese online platform like Twitter) has been run to better conduct governance.
This project was focused on a typical set of official accounts run by departments of the local government in a particular district.</description></item></channel></rss>